I'm from suite 16 studio.
I'm here to talk to you about soundproofing your recording studio.
On this building I have T-111 siding on the outside, which is a standard cardboard siding that you will find on many homes.
It's pretty good for stopping sound, but not quite as good as plywood would be.
If I were building this home from the ground up, or I wanted to make this better, I would put T-111 over the plywood and then put shingles over that.
But I'm more concerned with working on the inside of my building; and that's where I spent my money for this building was on the inside walls.
We're going to go in there and show you a little of that in a moment.
The building here is done with a cement slab with two by four construction, an 'A' frame ceiling and and 'A' frame roof with shingles on the roof.
Now that's another problem area we are going to talk about a little bit more.
Whenever you have a roof with an 'A' shape, you want to insulate that in a certain way.
You want to insulate the top 'A' frame portion of it and also you want to insulate across your beams that make you?re inside ceiling so you've got two layers of insulation in the ceiling.
That really helps keep the sound from going up.
Another consideration is: if I do have a cement block wall construction on a cement block slab, I've really got to be concerned about my roof because that is where all my sound is going to leak out of.
If I build a standard 'A' frame type roof, I'm going to really want to insulate it and definitely use 2x6 or 2x8 construction.